Guide to the John Tabor Kempe Papers 1678-1782 (bulk 1752-1774) MS 344
New-York Historical Society
- Series 1: Court Case Records, 1678-1778 (bulk 1752-1774), and Undated, 1678-1778 and Undated
  - Subseries 2: Supreme Court of Judicature, Civil
    - [James Jackson ex dem] Belitje Reneaudet [Renaudet] and others vs. [John Stiles] John Barret: Ejectment, 1764-1767 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Trial in Ulster County. Case includes rule, notice of trial, brief, and notices.
    - Beverly Robinson qui tam vs. Edward Gray, 1767 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      See also Beverly Robinson qui tam vs. Benjamin Palmer in Supreme Court of Judicature, case of Daniel Nimham in Governor and Council. See letter from Edward Gray to John Tabor Kempe, dated 12 February, 1767. Case includes notice of bail, exception to bail, and bond. Bond says The King vs. Gray.
    - Beverly Robinson qui tam vs. Benjamin Palmer, 1767 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      See also a letter from Isiah Bennett to Beverly Robinson, dated 22 December, 1770. Related cases include Beverly Robinson qui tam vs. Edward Gray, Supreme Court of Judicature. Case of Daniel Nimham in Governor and Council. Case includes notice of bail, note, and memo.
    - Burton Robinson vs. James Holmes and Gersham Mott, 1766-1767 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      See also Levin Milby against Holmes and Mott. See correspondence from Holmes and Mott to John Dagworthy, 28 December, 1766; John Dagworthy to John Tabor Kempe, 30 December, 1766; John Tabor Kempe to William Clayton, 13 April, 1767. Case includes notice of bail, plea, narratio, and notice of trial.
    - Alexander Rotherford vs. Robert Rotherford, 1770 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Cornelia Rutgers and Thomas Pennington vs. George Spencer, 1759 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - [James Jackson ex dem] Hendrick Schenck, Robert Brett, Matthew Brett, Rumbout Brett, Abraham Brinkerhoff, and Sarah Brinkerhoff vs. [John Stiles] Peter Ledew: Ejectment, 1770-1772 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Case includes narration, rule to file issue role, notice of motion for judgment, affidavit, rule and plea.
    - [James Jackson ex dem] Ryer Schermerhorn vs. [John Stiles] Simon Van Petten [Patten]: Ejectment, 1768, 1761-1762 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Earlier material from Albany Court of Common Pleas. See correspondence between John Tabor Kempe and Rutger Bleecker. See also John Tabor Kempe to Ryer Schermerhorn, dated 1 October, 1772. Case includes notice of trial, affidavits, common rule, narratio, notes on trial, examinations, copy of patent, and brief.
    - [Peter Quiet ex dem] Michael Schlater vs. Samuel Atwood, Benajah Rude, Henry Wallbridge, and Samuel Safford: Ejectment, 1771 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Trial in Albany County. All cases on the same sheet. Case includes notes.
    - John Scott vs. Henry Chase, 1770-1772 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Trial in Ulster County. See also correspondence between John Tabor Kempe and Henry Chase. See also John Nicoll to John Tabor Kempe dated 22 September, 1770. Case includes plea, notice of bail, change of venue notes, depositions, narratio, notice of trial, and character notices.
    - Robert and Mary Scott vs. William Chase [Chace] [Chease]: Trespass and assault, 1763 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      See also Robert Leake vs. William Chase in Supreme Court of Judicature. Case includes narratio, plea, notice of trial, and replication.
    - Thomas Scott vs. Henry Van Schaack: Debt, 1765 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Case includes notice of trial, notice of exception to bail, narratio, plea, notice of bail, and notice of special bail.
    - John Seaman to Benjamin Birdsell [Birdsall]: Assault and battery, 1774-1775 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Trial in Queens County. See correspondence between John Seaman and John Tabor Kempe. Case includes narratio, statement of case, list of witnesses, notice of trial,plea, and countermand notice of trial.
    - [James Jackson ex dem] Antenette and John Sedam vs. [John Stiles] James Lamb: Ejectment, 1771-1774 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Case includes common rule, ejectment, costs, and notice of motion for non suit.
    - Andrew Seton vs. John Lloyd Jr., 1770-1771 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Case includes notice of motion to change venue, notice of trial, plea, note, trial notes, narratio, brief, and statement of case.
    - John Shute and the King vs. Joseph Rodman: Trespass and assault, 1760-1761 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Trial in New York City and Westchester County. Filed in Supreme Court of Judicature, Civil. Court source found in the John Tabor Kempe papers, agendas, 1761. Also includes an account of fees. Case seems to have originated in County Sessions, Westchester as The King vs. Rodman. It is on Kempe's agenda as Shute vs. Rodman, but is the same incident. Case includes narratio, memo, and certificate.
    - Sampson Simson vs. Elijah Baldwin: Debt, 1771-1772 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Case includes calculation and narratio.
    - Sampson Simson vs. Henry Rosekrans: Debt, 1772 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Trial in Dutchess County and includes a draft narratio.
    - Robert Sinclair vs. Thomas Swords: Debt, 1775 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      See also correspondence between John Tabor Kempe and Thomas Swords; John Tabor Kempe to Thomas Smith, 13 January, 1775; Robert Henry to John Tabor Kempe, 11 October, 1774; and Thomas Smith to John Tabor Kempe, 11 March, 1775. Case includes narratio, notice of bail, notice of trial, replication, and plea.
    - Robert Sinclair vs. Samuel Broome, 1773-1774 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Case includes notice of bail, narratio, plea, notice of trial, affidavits, and rule.
    - Robert Sinclair vs. Abraham Rice, 1773 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Case includes a report of referees and part of a judgement roll.
    - John Peterse [Petrus] Smith vs. Johannes Snedeker [Snedicker] and Garret Snedeker [Snedicker], executors of Joseph Paul [Pall], 1770 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      Case includes subpeona, affidavits, and certiorari.
    - [James Jackson et dem] Thomas Smith vs. [John Stiles] Peter Hance and James Lamb: Ejectment, 1774-1775 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      Trial in Orange County. Case includes notice, affidavit for movement of venue, and narration.
    - George Spencer qui tam vs. George Harison, William Kelly, Waddel [Waddell] Cunningham, Theophilact Bache, James DePeyster, Lawrence Reade, Robert Dale, David Van Horne, Elias Debrosses, John Milligan, Judah Hays, Francis Welsh [Welch], Samuel Tingley, Philip Branson, and Michael Wade, 1760 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      Cases filed together, but may all be seperate cases. See other George Spencer cases in Court of Vice-Admiralty. See correspondence from George Spencer to John Tabor Kempe. Case includes costs.
    - Jacob Stinebrenner vs. John Leary, 1771 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Case includes copy of notice of taxing costs, notice of trial, notice of bail, plea, subpeona, list of witnesses, replication, accounts, additional count, narratio, affidavits, notices, brief, trial notes, and costs.
    - [James Jackson ex dem] Nicholas W. Stuyvesant vs. William Harrison: Ejectment, 1771 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Case includes notice for restriking jury.
    - [James Jackson ex dem] Thomas Swords and others vs. [John Stiles] Hendricus Ousterhout: Ejectment and trespass, 1769-1773 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      See also correspondence: John Tabor Kempe to Thomas Sword [various]; John Tabor Kempe to Sherriff of Queens County, 14 September, 1771; John Tabor Kempe to Thomas Thorne and Oliver Waters, 3 August, 1772; John Tabor Kempe to William Cockburn [various]. Case includes bond, notes, notices, list of jurors, countermand notice of trial, instructions, notice of trial, rules and plea, affidavits, brief, venire and panel, narratio, costs, rule, and directions for serving an ejectment.
    - Robert Taylor vs. Robert Sinclair, 1774-1775 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Case includes rule to plead, narratio, plea, receipt, notice of bail, calculations, and costs.
    - [James Jackson ex dem] Daniel Terbos and others vs. Johannes Hardenbergh Jr. [and others]: Ejectment, 1767 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Trial in Ulster County. Case includes notes, information, notice of trial, notices, and notes of point of law.
    - [James Jackson ex dem] Daniel Terbos and others vs. Peter DuBois: Ejectment, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Case includes notes.
    - [James Jackson ex dem] Jacobus Terbos vs. [John Stiles] Lawrence Lawrence: Ejectment, 1774-1775 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Trial in Dutchess County. Case includes rule, countermand notice of trial, notice of trial, opinion, and narratio.
    - Hendrick and Simon Terbos, executors of Hendrick Terbos vs. Peter Vandewater: Debt, 1770-1772 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Trial in Dutchess County. See also a letter from Peter Vandewater to John Tabor Kempe, dated 8 January, 1771. Case includes affidavit to ground certiorari, notes for motion to quash proceedings, affidavits of former jurors, and justices account.
    - Michael Thodey vs. Henry Pulline [Pullen]: Assault, 1769 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      The case includes a brief.
    - Stephen Thorne [Thorn], Thomas Moore, and Francis Welsh vs. George Evans, 1758 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Case involves the Sloop Jane and includes deposition, notes of evidence, and brief.
    - Michael and Elizabeth Tingle vs. Crean Brush: Trespass and assault, 1762-1763 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Case includes a declaration.
    - Frederick Tobias vs. Zachariah Dubois, 1771-1772 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      See correspondence from Isaac Tobias to John Tabor Kempe, 14 October, 1771 and Fredirck Tobias to John Tabor Kempe, 14 October, 1771. Case includes affidavits, notices, character statements, and narratio.
    - Andrew Todd vs. Joshua Hallack: Trespass and debt, 1765 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Trial in Orance County and New York City. Case includes writ and account of principal.
    - Samuel Touchet and Hugh Wallace vs. David Pryce, 1773 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - John Troy vs. David Price [Pryce], 1761-1766 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      See John Troy to Captain Coffler [Koffler], 19 October, 1762, and John Troy to David Price [Pryce], 20 October, 1762. Case includes bond, affidavits, declaration, plea, trial, notes, notice of trial, notices, and brief.
    - John Van Alen vs. Harmanus Schuyler: Assault, 1772 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      See also correspondence between John Tabor Kampe and John Van Alen. See also John Tabor Kempe to Peter Silvester, 18 September, 1772. Case includes brief, notice of trial, replication, rejoinder, memos, plea, narratio, and costs.
    - Lawrence and Agnes Vanderhoof vs. Philip Thompson: Trespass, 1775 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Case includes notice of trial, plea, memo, subpeona, narratio, and note of evidence.
    - Cornelius Van Der Voort [Vandervoort] vs. Leffert Lefferts: Trespass, assault, and battery, 1775 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Trial in Kings County. See also Leffert Lefferts vs. Cornelius Van Der Voort [Vandervoort] and Elizabeth Bennet. Case includes replication, narratio, and notice of trial.
    - [James Jackson ex dem] Jacob Van Schaick vs. John Gansevoort: Ejectment, 1767 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Trial in Albany County.
    - [James Jackson ex dem] Catherine Van Renselaer [Van Renselar] vs. Simon Johannis Veeder, Volkert Veeder, Simon M. Veeder, and Abraham Veeder: Ejectment, 1774 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Trial in Albany County. Case includes affidavits, brief, narratio, balloting, common rule, and notices.
    - [James Jackson ex dem] John Van Renselaer and others vs. [John Stiles] Thomas Whitney; John McArthur; Thomas Millard; James Bagby; Zachariah Squire; Richard Wahn; Pierce Walter; William Kellogg; Joseph Clark; Nathaniel Colver, 1765 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Document contains ten seperate cases. Case includes a warrant of attorny.
    - [James Jackson ex dem] Stephen Van Renselaer vs. Abraham Lansing: Ejectment, 1767 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Case includes affidavit and scrap.
    - [Peter Quiet ex dem] Samuel Verplanck vs. Hendrick Schenck: Ejectment, 1772 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Trial in Dutchess County. See also [Peter Quiet ex dem] Lawrence Lawrence vs. Mathias Volentine. Case includes notice of motion, notes, and brief.
    - [Peter Quiet ex dem] Gideon Ver Vielen vs. Peter Outwater and Jury Hoffman: Ejectment, 1774 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Trial in Dutchess County. Case includes brief and notice of trial.
    - [Peter Quiet ex dem] Lawrence Lawrence vs. Mathias Volentine: Ejectment, 1772 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Trial in Dutchess County. Filed with [Peter Quiet ex dem] Samuel Ver Planck vs. Hendrick Schenck. Case includes notice of motion and brief.
    - Henry Van Schaack and Robert McGinnis vs. Richard Sharpe, 1765 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      See also the following correspondence: John Pratt to unknown, 1 April, 1766; William Cairns to John Lamb, 3 December, 1763 and 3 November, 1763; Torrans Greg and Roag to John Lamb, 26 July, 1764; William Cairns to McGinnis and Van Schaack, 3 November, 1763; and Henry Van Schaack to John Tabor Kempe, 22 October, 1765. Case includes notice of trial, subpeona, brief, narratio, statement of case, plea, notice of bail, declaration, affidavits, and depostions.
    - Patrick Walsh vs. Thomas Franklin Jr.: Debt, 1773 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      See correspondence from Whitehead Hicks to John Tabor Kempe, dated 20 April, 1773. Case includes plea, notice of trial, subpeonas, brief, notes, and narratio.
    - David Waugh vs. Robert White, 1770 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      See also White vs. Waugh in Chancery. See correspondence from Robert White to John Tabor Kempe dated 11 March, 1772 and 6 October, 1772.
    - Edward Welch and [Margaret Welch] vs. Charles Prosser, 1760-1761 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      See also Prosser vs. Welch in Supreme Court of Judicature. They appear to be part of the same incident and suing each other for assault. Both cases are on John Tabor Kempe's agenda for 1760. See John Tabor Kempe to Thomas Smith, 17 April, 1761. Case includes plea, receipt, and narratio.
    - Peter Silvester and Beverly Robinson, assigns of est. of Henry Van Schaack vs. John Wetherhead, 1771 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Filed with John Wetherhead vs. John Baptist Wendell [Wendel], shared documents. Case includes notice of bail and rule of reference.
    - John Wetherhead vs. James Ryker, 1767 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Case includes declaration and narratio.
    - John Wetherhead vs. John Baptist Wendell [Wendel], 1770 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      See additional correspondence: Harmanus Schoyler to John Tabor Kempe, 24 November, 1770; John Wetherhead to John Tabor Kempe, April 1771.
    - [James Jackson ex dem] John Wetherhead [Weatherhead] and Catherine Morris vs. [John Stiles] Parker Wickham: Ejectment, 1769 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Case includes rule, plea, and narratio.
    - Johana Whealan [Wealin], admin. Of David Whealan [Wealin] vs. John Milligan: Debt, 1760 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      See correspondence from John Tabor Kempe to Johana Whealan, 2 September, 1760; William Gallagher to John Tabor Kempe, 5 July, 1762; and John Tabor Kempe to John Milligan, 27 September, 1759. Case includes declaration, plea, letter of attorney, letters of administration, and statement of case.
    - [Peter Quiet] Daniel Whipple vs. Atherton [Altherton] Chaffe and Robert Stout, 1773 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Trial in Cumberland County. Case includes warrant of attorney, common rule, and declaration of ejectment.
    - John Whitelock vs. John Wetherhead, 1772 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Case includes notice of exception and notice of bail.
    - John Widger [Wedger] vs. John Johnson, 1760-1763 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      See also Walter Wood vs. John Johnson. Documents for both cases are filed under Widger vs. Johnson. See correspondence from John Widger to John Tabor Kempe dated 11 August, 1761.
    - [Erasmus Williams et al] "His Creditors" vs. John Beekman: Debt, 1770-1771 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Creditors include Erasmus Williams. Affidavits of Erasmus Williams, Marinus Willett, and Benjamin Quereau. Case includes reports of Chief Justices, affidavits, warrant of attachment, and description of lot.
    - Walter Wood vs. John Johnson: Trespass and debt, 1760 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      See also Widger vs. John Johnson. Documents for both cases are filed under Widger vs. Johnson. Case includes declaration, affidavits, brief, replication, plea, account, notices of bail, and notices.
  - Subseries 3: Chancery Court
    - William Bryant vs. Sarah Byvanck, 1753 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Demand of goods of Dennis Bryant, deceased mariner, being held by Sarah Byvanck. Inclides detailed list of items owned by Dennis Bryant.
    - Thomas Annely vs. Francis Lewis, 1758 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      See correspondence from Elizabeth Annely to William Kempe, dated 6 October, 1755 and Thomas Annely to William Kempe, 29 May, 1758. Case includes bill and instructions.
    - Elias Bland vs. John Bailey, 1773 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Rev. Joshua Bloomer vs. Robert Hickman [Hinchman] and Philip Edsal [Edsall], 1774 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Edward Bailey [Bayley], Edward and Anne Smith, John and Margaret Norcross, Susannah Metcalf, and Peggy Winstanley vs. James Buvelot [Bevelot] and John Field: Estate dispute, 1773-1775 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Hairs of John Wright vs. his executors. See also a draft of a letter from Buvelot on July 8, 1722 and to Hamilton Young on July 28, 1775.
    - Daniel Blouin vs. George Wittmer [Witmer] [Witmar], 1772-1775 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Folder 1 of 2. Some documents in Supreme Court of Judicature. See also Wittmer vs. Blouin in Chancery and The King vs. Wittmer and John Haumaid, Supreme Court of Judicature. See correspondence from William Glajon and Daniel Blouin to John Tabor Kempe. Case includes accounts, notices, affidavits, notes, statement of case, interr, petition, bond of indemnification, answer, rejoinder, replication, rules, writ, and bill.
    - Daniel Blouin vs. George Wittmer [Witmer] [Witmar], 1772-1775 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Folder 2 of 2. Some of the documents are in Supreme Court of Judicature. See also Wittmer vs. Blouin in Chancery and The King vs. Wittmer and John Haumaid in Supreme Court of Judicature. Case includes accounts, notices, affidavits, notes, statement of case, interr, petition, bond of indemnification, answer, rejoinder, replication, rules, writ, and bill.
    - David Clarkson Jr. and Matthew Clarkson vs. Levinus Clarkson, Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - John De Noyelles vs. William Bayard, Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - James Duane vs. Cornelius Vander Voort [Vandervoort], Isaac Jansen, Jr., and Garret Jansen, 1771 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Dispute over slaves.
    - Christian Heartman vs. Shadrack Merchant et al., 1766 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Thomas Jones and Susannah De Lancey vs. Town of Kingston, 1772 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - James Leadbetter vs. George Harison, George Folliott, Richard Nicholls, and Jane Harison, 1770-1774 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Folder 1 of 3. See also Leadbetter vs. Harison. Case includes bill of reviver, accounts, statement, answer, affs, notes, jury list, bill, notices, orders, replication, notice of trial, answer (copy), subpeona, referee's report, injunction, and rule of reference.
    - James Leadbetter vs. George Harison, George Folliott, Richard Nicholls, [and Jane Harison], 1770-1774 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      Folder 2 of 3. See also Leadbetter vs. Harison in Supreme Court of Judicature. Case includes bill of reviver, accounts, statement, answer, affs, notes, jury list, bill, notices, orders, replication, notice of trial, answer (copy), subpeona, referee's rpt, injunction, and rule of reference.
    - James Leadbetter vs. George Harison, George Folliott, Richard Nicholls, [and Jane Harison], 1770-1774 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Folder 3 of 3. See also Leadbetter vs. Harison in Supreme Court of Judicature. Case includes bill of reviver, accounts, statement, answer, affs, notes, jury list, bill, notices, orders, replication, notice of trial, answer (copy), subpeona, referee's rpt, injunction, and rule of reference.
    - John Milledoller et al. vs. Susannah and Peter Vergereau, William and Susannah Tenant, 1771-1772 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      See letter from Thomas Smith to John Tabor Kempe, dated February 27, 1772.
    - Hermanus Myer [Meyer] vs. Palulus Ploeg [Plough], Cornelius Van Bueren, Johannes Jansen, Johannes DuBois Jr., Johannes Snyder Jr., Petrus Crispel, Trans Hendricks, and Dirck Wynkoop Jr., 1763-1767 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Defendants elders and deacons of the Reformed Protestant Dutch Church of Kingston, Ulster Co. See correspondece for additional material. Case includes notes, bill, affidavits, notices, summons, decree, bill and answer.
    - Peter Pemberton, William and Nelly Winstanley vs. James Buvelot [Bevelot] [Beuelot] and John Field: Estate dispute, 1773-1775 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      See also Edward Bailey et al vs. James Buvelot and John Field. See also a draft letter from John Tabor Kempe to Hamilton Young, July 28, 1775.
    - Joseph Roberjot [Robergott] vs. Sampson Simson [Simpson], 1772 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      See Roberjot to Sampson and Solomon Simson, dated April 19, 1770.
    - Richard Sharpe vs. William Cairns, John Lamb, Henry Van Schaack, and Robert McGinnis, 1765-1773 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      See John Lamb to John Tabor Kempe, 16 February, 1773. See also Henry Van Schaack and Robert McGinnis vs. Richard Sharpe, Supreme Court of Judicature. Case includes notices, costs, notes, inter, answer, replication, and bill.
    - William Johnston vs. William Tongue, Eve Provoost, Samuel Provoost, and Mary Provoost, 1774 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Filed with Tongue vs. Johnston.
    - William Tongue vs. William Johnston [Johnson]: Debt, 1774 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - John Van Alstyne vs. Tuenis Van Slych [Van Slyck], 1773 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      See also correspondence between John Tabor Kempe and Rutger Bleacker. See also correspondence from John Tabor Kempe to John Van Alstyne dated 17 February, 1774 and 25 November, 1774.
    - Johannes Van Beverhoudt [Beuerhoudt], Peter Winne, Mary Van Beverhoudt, and Barent Van Beure vs. Nicholas Bayard, 1771-1772 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Folder 1 of 2. Estate of Margrita Bayard involved. See also John Tabor Kempe to Nicholas Bayard, January 4, 1770.
    - Johannes Van Beverhoudt [Beuerhoudt], Peter Winne, Mary Van Beverhoudt, and Barent Van Beure vs. Nicholas Bayard, heir and executor of Nicholas Bayard, 1771-1772 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Folder 2 of 2. The case involves the estate of Margrita Bayard. A bulk of the cases are in Court of Chancery and two documents are in Supreme Court of Judicature. See letter from John Tabor Kempe to Nicholas Bayard, dated 4 January, 1770.
    - Thomas Walton, Abraham Walton, Gerard Walton, John Ray, Walter Franklin, and Samuel Franklin vs. Ebenezer Boyd and Catherine Lynsen: Mortgage payment, 1769 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - John Wetherhead, adm of Abraham Lodge vs. Whitehead Hicks, Augustus Van Cortlandt, and Robert Cromelius, 1766-1767 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Robert White vs. David Waugh: Trespass, 1771-1772 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      See also Waugh vs. White in Supreme Court of Judicature. See correspondence from Robert White to John Tabor Kempe dated 6 October, 1772. Case includes certs, notices, bill, answer, and exceptions.
    - George Wittmer [Witmer] [Witmar] vs. Daniel Blouin [Sampson Simson and Solomon Simson], 1772-1774 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      See also Blouin vs. Wittmer in Chancery and King vs. Wittmer and John Haumaid, Supreme Court of Judicature. See also correspondence between William Clajon and Daniel Blouin to John Tabor Kempe. Case includes draft of answer, bill, replication, notices, rejoinder, exceptions, petitions, affs, notices of bail, and notice of taxing costs.
  - Subseries 4: Other Courts
    - James Thompson vs. William Richards, 1769 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Court of Chancery
    - The King vs. Benjamin Moore, 1752 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Court of Vice-Admirality
    - Opinion, 1752 (Box 9, Folder 7)